<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Contributing on Birdwatch Guide</title>
    <link>https://twitter.github.io/birdwatch/contributing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Contributing on Birdwatch Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://twitter.github.io/birdwatch/contributing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Signing up</title>
      <link>https://twitter.github.io/birdwatch/contributing/signing-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://twitter.github.io/birdwatch/contributing/signing-up/</guid>
      <description>During the first phase of the pilot, Birdwatch is limited to a small test group in the US.
Our goal is to expand Birdwatch to the global Twitter community. We want anyone to be able to participate and know that the more diverse the community, the better Birdwatch will be at effectively addressing misinformation. We’ll draw on learnings from this initial test and, over time, scale safely.
Sign up here     Eligibility To participate in the pilot, accounts must have:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downloading data</title>
      <link>https://twitter.github.io/birdwatch/contributing/download-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://twitter.github.io/birdwatch/contributing/download-data/</guid>
      <description>We can&amp;rsquo;t wait to learn with you!
All Birdwatch contributions are publicly available on the Download Data page of the Birdwatch site so that anyone in the US has free access to analyze the data, identify problems, and spot opportunities to make Birdwatch better.
If you have questions or feedback about the Birdwatch public data or would like to share your analyses of this data with us, please DM us at @Birdwatch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examples</title>
      <link>https://twitter.github.io/birdwatch/contributing/examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://twitter.github.io/birdwatch/contributing/examples/</guid>
      <description>Great Birdwatch notes follow the program&amp;rsquo;s values: They build understanding, are written in good faith, and are helpful even to those who disagree.
   &amp;ldquo;Whales aren&amp;rsquo;t real&amp;rdquo;   Here&amp;rsquo;s a Tweet making misleading claims about whales, followed by helpful and unhelpful Birdwatch notes:
Whales are not actually mammals. If Humans (land mammals) can’t drink seawater — just try it! — how can supposed sea mammals like whales stay hydrated?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rating notes</title>
      <link>https://twitter.github.io/birdwatch/contributing/rating-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://twitter.github.io/birdwatch/contributing/rating-notes/</guid>
      <description>There are two ways to find Tweets with Birdwatch notes in order to rate their quality:
Rating notes on the Birdwatch site Go to the Birdwatch Site&amp;rsquo;s Home page and choose any Tweet to see notes that participants have added to it. There are three main timelines on this page:
  Needs your help: Contains Tweets with notes where you can have the most impact when rating. This tab is only visible to pilot participants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Submit Feedback</title>
      <link>https://twitter.github.io/birdwatch/contributing/feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://twitter.github.io/birdwatch/contributing/feedback/</guid>
      <description>Birdwatch is early in its development, and our goal is to build it in the open with the public. We invite you on this journey to learn and shape Birdwatch alongside us. Feel free to reach out with:
 Questions about the program Problems or issues you experience while contributing Risks and concerns we might not have considered Ideas for product updates or features for our roadmap Analyses done with our public data or feedback about the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Values</title>
      <link>https://twitter.github.io/birdwatch/contributing/values/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://twitter.github.io/birdwatch/contributing/values/</guid>
      <description>Birdwatch aims to provide context on Tweets in a way that a broad set of people with diverse perspectives find helpful. We ask that all Birdwatch contributors agree to uphold three core values:
  Contribute to build understanding   Birdwatch seeks to provide helpful context so people can stay better informed about Tweets they see. It’s not a place for quick dunks, personal opinions, or insults. Write clear, evidence-based notes to help everyone, even skeptics, better understand a Tweet and why it might be misleading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing notes</title>
      <link>https://twitter.github.io/birdwatch/contributing/writing-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://twitter.github.io/birdwatch/contributing/writing-notes/</guid>
      <description>Anyone in the US can read Birdwatch notes, but only pilot participants can add new notes to Tweets. Here&amp;rsquo;s how to add a note:
 Click or tap the ••• menu on the Tweet&amp;rsquo;s top right and then Contribute to Birdwatch.     Before starting, you’ll see a reminder about Birdwatch values — a prompt to promote helpful contributions.
  Answer the required multiple choice questions. These are designed to understand, in a structured way, why a Tweet might or might not be misleading.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
